

▼ fdjeumou@utexas.edu | 🌴 franckdjeumou.github.io | 🖸 wuwushrek | 🛅 franck-djeumou-626613202 | 🔞 Franck Djeumou

Research Interests_

My research lies broadly at the intersection of learning with prior knowledge, control theory, formal methods, and optimization. Specifically, I investigate how prior knowledge (e.g., laws of Physics, properties empirically validated through engineering experiments) can be incorporated into learning agents to improve the data efficiency and generalization, and how such side information can be used for the formal verification of the agents, particularly in the context of safety-critical applications such as aircraft control and robotics.

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING Fall 2018 - Now (Expected in Spring 2023)

• Ph.D. Advisor: Ufuk Topcu

• Cumulative GPA Over 30 Credits (Ph.D. Major Course Requirements) - 3.96

ISAE-SUPAERO (Institut Supérieur de l'Aéronautique et de l'Espace)

September 2014 - June 2018

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE AND MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

- · Advised by Prof. Jerome Hugues
- Cumulative GPA: 3.8 | Top 4% of the class
- Thesis on "Safety Guarantees for Drones through Set-Based Formal Verification Methods"

École Polytechnique

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMASIC) September 2016 - September 2017

- · Advised by Prof. Eric Goubault and Prof. Sylvie Putot
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7 | Graduated with Honours
- Thesis on "Human-Embedded Autonomous Flight Under Formal Task Specifications"
- This master degree was obtained as a collaboration between ISAE-SUPAERO and École Polytechnique

Lycée Fénelon

CLASS PREPARATORY (JUNIOR UNDERGRADUATE LEVEL) IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS, AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011 - September 2014

· 6th out of 42 students

Experience

Autonomous Systems Group

Austin, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

September 2018 - Present

- · My research lies at the intersection of learning with prior knowledge, control theory, formal methods, and optimization
- Published 9 conference papers (with 5 papers currently being reviewed) and 6 journal papers (with 3 papers currently being reviewed)

Cosynus Team at Laboratory LIX of École Polytechnique

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISORS: ERIC GOUBAULT AND SYLVIE PUTOT

March 2018 - August 2018

- Build the quadrotor testbed for the team based on Crazyflie drones
- · Develop a hardware and software in the loop, Gazebo-based swarm simulator for the Crazyflie drones
- · Investigate safety of dynamical systems through Taylor-based methods and abstract interpretation
- · On-the-fly, lightweight, real-time verification (reach and safety properties) algorithms to be embedded on the Crazyflie drones

Autonomous System Group (UT Austin)

Austin, USA

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

March 2017 - August 2017

- Design and build quadrotors based on the Snapdragon Platform with PX4 as the autopilot. Implementation of a fast trajectory generator for quadrotors based on the minimum snap approach and a new problem modeling
- Human interface with virtual reality and autonomous flight of a quadrotor via eye-tracking.
- · Tracking of stochastically moving targets using POMDP (Partially Observable Markov Decision Process) and human input
- Model checking and planning of UAVs autonomous missions with specifications written in linear temporal logic (LTL)

Liebherr Aerospace and Transportation

Toulouse, France

June 2015 - August 2015 MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

- · Implementation in R of supervised learning algorithms to automatically classify aircraft's equipments from a reliability point of view
- · Design and implement a human machine interface in Java that interacts with Liebherr's database and provide to a user the classification's result

FRANCK DJEUMOU · HTTPS://FRANCKDJEUMOU.GITHUB.IO



Languages French (native), English (fluent), Japanese (beginner) **Programming** Python, C++, C, JAVA, C#, R, Matlab, HTML5/CSS3

Tools & Technologies ROS, Jax, TensorFlow, Unity, Gazebo, PX4 Autopilot, MuJoCo, RTOS, Gurobi, Mosek, Arduino

Sports Tennis, Soccer, Running, Biking, Skiing

Publications

* indicates equal contribution

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE ARTICLES [9]

Taylor-Lagrange Neural Ordinary Differential Equations: Toward Fast Training and Evaluation of Neural ODEs Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu Under Review at International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022 URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.05715 2022 Neural Networks with Physics-Informed Architectures and Constraints for Dynamical Systems Modeling Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu Under Review at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022 URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06407 2021 Learning to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial: Data-Driven Control with Scarce Data and Side Information Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu Under Review at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022 URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.10533 2021 Task-Guided Inverse Reinforcement Learning Under Partial Information Franck Djeumou, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu Under Review at International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS) 2022 URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14073 Blending Controllers via Multi-Objective Bandits Parham Gohari*, Franck Djeumou*, Abraham P Vinod, Ufuk Topcu Under review at the 2022 American Control Conference (ACC) as an invited paper URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15755 2021 Learning-Based, Safety-Constrained Control from Scarce Data via Reciprocal Barriers Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu IEEE Conference on Decision and Control URL: https://cverginis.github.io/publications/conferences/CDC21_safety.pdf On-the-fly, data-driven reachability analysis and control of unknown systems: an F-16 aircraft case study Franck Djeumou, Aditya Zutshi, Ufuk Topcu International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (HSCC 2021), Best Demo/Poster Award URL: https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3447928.3457355 On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Smooth Systems from Limited Data Franck Djeumou, Abraham P. Vinod, Éric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu 2021 American Control Conference (ACC) URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9483367 Probabilistic Swarm Guidance Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications

JOURNAL ARTICLES [6]

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)

Task-Guided IRL on POMDPs at Scale with Information Asymmetry

URL: http://www.roboticsproceedings.org/rss16/p058.pdf

Franck Djeumou, Christian Ellis, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at the special issue VSI:Risk-Aware Autonomy for consideration at the journal of Artificial Intelligence (2022). Elsevier

Probabilistic control of heterogeneous swarms subject to graph temporal logic specifications: A decentralized and scalable approach

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Murat Cubuktepe, Ufuk Topcu

Conditionally accepted at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEE TAC) (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.15729

Safety-Constrained Learning and Control using Scarce Data and Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, **Franck Djeumou**, Ufuk Topcu *Under Review* at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06526

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Systems: From Side Information to Performance Guarantees through Reachability

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P Vinod, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu Under Review at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.05524

Policy synthesis for switched linear systems with Markov decision process switching

Bo Wu, Murat Cubuktepe, **Franck Djeumou**, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

2021

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.12733

Online synthesis for runtime enforcement of safety in multi-agent systems

Dhananjay Raju, Sudarshanan Bharadwaj, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Control of Network Systems (2021). IEEE

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9362272

2021

Honors & Awards_

2021	Winner , Best Demo/Poster Award at Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Hybrid Systems:	Nashville, USA
2021	Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)	
2017	Scholarship, Foundation of Ecole Polytechnique	Palaiseau, France
2017	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2016	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2015	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2014	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France

Professional Services

WORKSHOPS ORGANIZED

Workshop on Safe and Reliable Robot Autonomy under Uncertainty

Philadelphia, USA

May 2022

Co-organizer

REVIEWER

I was a reviewer at the following journals and conferences.

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

- IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021)
- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (2021)
- American Control Conference (2020, 2021)
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (2021)
- IFAC symposium system identification (2021)

Invited Talks_

2021	Incorporating Physics-Based Knowledge into Neural Network Dynamics Models, Galois Inc: Final Briefing for the Assured Autonomy Project	Austin, USA
2021	Learning How to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial,	Austin, USA
	Professor Karen E. Willcox's Research Group	
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin. USA
	Lockheed Martin	71031111, 03/1
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin, USA
	Texas Robotics Symposium	
2021	Data-Driven, On-The-Fly Reachability and Control of Unknown Systems,	
	Mini-Symposium on "Leaning for Dynamical Systems and Control" at the SIAM Conference on Applications of	Portland, USA
	Dynamical Systems	
2020	Learning On-the-Fly with a Case Study in Hypersonic Flight,	Austin, USA
	Sandia National Laboratories: Autonomy for Hypersonics Virtual Field Day	

References_

- Prof. Ufuk Topcu, Assistant Professor (Controls, Autonomy and Robotics), The University of Texas at Austin, USA
- Prof. Eric Goubault, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France
- Prof. Sylvie Putot, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France